<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cognitive Robotics on UNKNOWN SPACE</title>
    <link>https://shuoyin03.github.io/tags/cognitive-robotics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cognitive Robotics on UNKNOWN SPACE</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shuoyin03.github.io/tags/cognitive-robotics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cognitive Robotics - Deep Learning in Robotics</title>
      <link>https://shuoyin03.github.io/2024/02/19/cognitive-robotics-deep-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shuoyin03.github.io/2024/02/19/cognitive-robotics-deep-learning/</guid>
      <description>This blog is a supplement of deep learning topic as we already explain the fundamental knowledge in this blog: Natural Language Processing - Deep Learning I, where we will mainly focuses on CNN.
Why Deep Learning? The reason why we apply deep learning techniques are quite obvious, which is to ues it handle thee robots&amp;rsquo; vision. The advantage of neural network is learning and building up features to represent the input data, which help us remove the complex and limit feature selection process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cognitive Robotics - Navigation</title>
      <link>https://shuoyin03.github.io/2024/02/19/cognitive-robotics-sensors-navigation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shuoyin03.github.io/2024/02/19/cognitive-robotics-sensors-navigation/</guid>
      <description>In this blog, we will discuss about the navigation - how will the robots go the destination we want them to go?
Navigation Navigation, which in definition it means moving the entire robot from one location to another, this question could also refers to some destination planning. The difference between navigation and manipulation is that, manipulation refers to the problems moving body part to manipulate the environment.
Locomotion Locomotion are the methods to achieve navigation, there are three types of locomotion:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cognitive Robotics - Sensors and Actuators</title>
      <link>https://shuoyin03.github.io/2024/02/14/cognitive-robotics-sensors-and-actuators/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shuoyin03.github.io/2024/02/14/cognitive-robotics-sensors-and-actuators/</guid>
      <description>A robot is mainly consist of 4 components, which is:
Physical Body Sensors Effectors and actuators Controller Here we will mainly talk about effectors, actuators and sensors.
Actuators, Effectors and Actions Effectors are any device that can make an effect on the environment, for example, the arms on human body or robot body. And Actuators are devices which enables effectors to execute movements. For example, muscles and electric motors. Note that one effector must have one actuator to support it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cognitive Robotics - Introduction</title>
      <link>https://shuoyin03.github.io/2024/02/05/cognitive-robotics-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shuoyin03.github.io/2024/02/05/cognitive-robotics-introduction/</guid>
      <description>What are Robots? A robot, is a machine capable of carrying out a complex series of actions automatically, especially one programmable by a computer. Also, it could be described as an autonomous system which exists in the physical world, can sense its environment, and can act on it to achieve some goals. There are many types of robots that we define today. For example, they are:
Humanoid Android Biomimetic Industrial (manipulation, navigation) Medical Assistive Humanoid Robots A humanoid robot has an anthropomorphic body plan and actuators with human-like senses for human-robot interaction.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
