<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Distributed System on UNKNOWN SPACE</title>
    <link>https://shuoyin03.github.io/tags/distributed-system/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Distributed System on UNKNOWN SPACE</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shuoyin03.github.io/tags/distributed-system/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Distributed System - Resource Management</title>
      <link>https://shuoyin03.github.io/2024/01/06/distributed-system-resource-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shuoyin03.github.io/2024/01/06/distributed-system-resource-management/</guid>
      <description>What are resources? All stuffs needed for maintaining the run of a system are called resources, such as hardware(CPU, storage, network links), software(web services), and datasets. Applications need to share the resources, and we need to consider how to optimize their use with respect to resources available and resources requested by different applications.
One example demonstrating a trade-off between time, price and storage resource is that, we could make a software parallelisable and run it with different expensive processors, but it uses lots of storage because large amount of data are processing at the same time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Distributed System - Fault Tolerance</title>
      <link>https://shuoyin03.github.io/2024/01/05/distributed-system-fault-tolerance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shuoyin03.github.io/2024/01/05/distributed-system-fault-tolerance/</guid>
      <description>In a distributed application, we always have to consider the impact of faults and solutions of how we can solve it while balancing the cost, response time and other performances.
Type of Failures First of all, let’s have a look at what type of faults do have.
Omission failures
The server fails to respond/receive to incoming requests and fail to send messages Timing failures
The server fails to respond within a certain time Response failures</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Distributed System - Performance Modelling</title>
      <link>https://shuoyin03.github.io/2023/12/13/distributed-system-performance-modelling/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shuoyin03.github.io/2023/12/13/distributed-system-performance-modelling/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is always good to test the performance of distributed applications to ensure it meets the target, and today we&amp;rsquo;ll learn what is a model and how to build a model to achieve this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Distributed System - Big data</title>
      <link>https://shuoyin03.github.io/2023/11/06/distributed-system-big-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shuoyin03.github.io/2023/11/06/distributed-system-big-data/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a shared nothing infrastructure, data storage, update, access and processing takes place across a collection of networked machines. To enhance the performance, processing needs to be take place in parallel, which we have to distribute data, and that&amp;rsquo;s partition. This article will gives an rough idea of partition techniques and details needs to be consider.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
