<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Scraping on UNKNOWN SPACE</title>
    <link>https://shuoyin03.github.io/tags/scraping/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Scraping on UNKNOWN SPACE</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://shuoyin03.github.io/tags/scraping/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sweden Companies Contacts Scraping - CEO &amp; Project Managers Emails</title>
      <link>https://shuoyin03.github.io/2025/07/24/sweden-contact-scraping/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shuoyin03.github.io/2025/07/24/sweden-contact-scraping/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;project-overview&#34;&gt;Project Overview&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The client’s website hosts a comprehensive list of companies in Sweden. The goal is to scrape the website and gather essential company information, including name, location, and organisation number. Additionally, the project aims to extract CEO and Project Manager (PM) emails from each company’s official website and output this data into a structured CSV file. The website client provides doesn&amp;rsquo;t include the official url, so google search API implementation is needed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wine Auction Management Admin Website - Million Data Scraping</title>
      <link>https://shuoyin03.github.io/2025/07/24/wine-auction-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shuoyin03.github.io/2025/07/24/wine-auction-management/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;project-overview&#34;&gt;Project Overview&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our Client is building the world biggest &lt;strong&gt;all-in-one wine auctions data center&lt;/strong&gt;, with aggregating data from over &lt;strong&gt;20+ well-known auctions houses&lt;/strong&gt;. All the data are publicly available on respective auction websites. The target data includes information about auctions and lots, for example, name, location, prices, volumes, estimated price, etc.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Given the client has a strong need of using these data for analytics and price comparisons, the platform must normalize all scraped wine data and map each item to the industry&amp;rsquo;s unique wine identifier—LWIN (Liv-ex Wine Identification Number). This requires large-scale fuzzy matching against a reference dataset of hundreds of thousands of standardized wine records.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
